<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cover on Michel de Bree</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/tags/cover/</link><description>Recent content in cover on Michel de Bree</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.micheldebree.nl/tags/cover/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Terminator 2 theme, from the Endoskull animation</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/endoskull/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/endoskull/</guid><description>I did a little update on the Terminator theme from Big Angry Sprite. It is made for Honcho&amp;rsquo;s entry for the Skull Animation Compo on CSDB: Endoskull. I did not have much time, but I think this version is somewhat of an improvement. And guess what, this little production won 1st place!
P.S. the movie above is taken from the Anniversary Edition, which was released after the competition, and adds a nice opening title screen.</description></item><item><title>Muppetshow Theme, from the demo Subway Art</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/muppetshow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/muppetshow/</guid><description>A cover of the theme from The Muppetshow, made for the successor of the Commodore 64 demo Mahna Mahna, called Subway Art
Again, the music was done by Animal. Nobody knows it&amp;rsquo;s my alter ego, except you, so hush hush&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Mahna Mahna, from the demo Mahna Mahna</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/mahnamahna/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/mahnamahna/</guid><description>Pssst&amp;hellip; I made the soundtrack to this Commodore 64 demo, but I did it incognito. Don&amp;rsquo;t tell anyone!</description></item><item><title>Big Angry Sprite; going back to my Commodore 64 roots</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/big_angry_sprite/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 08:24:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/big_angry_sprite/</guid><description>After 30 years of coding anything for the Commodore 64, I have released a small demo. Back in the 80s I started to teach myself programming on this machine, and I though it would be fun to revisit my coding roots.
The demoscene of the Commodore 64 is still very much alive, and seeing the amazing stuff that is coming out nowadays, I was motivated to try and add a little something to that.</description></item></channel></rss>