<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Michel de Bree</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/</link><description>Recent content on Michel de Bree</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 08:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.micheldebree.nl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I built a new personal website with Hugo</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/welcome/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/welcome/</guid><description>Welcome to my website. In this first post I will go over some details on how this site was created.
The site is static HTML, generated by Hugo Sourcecode is accessible on Github The generated HTML is hosted on Github pages Based on the hugo-coder theme So, I didn&amp;rsquo;t use a fancy CMS like Wordpress, or a platform like Medium for example. Why is that?
I don&amp;rsquo;t need fancy stuff that requires session management, a database, authorization etc.</description></item><item><title>Smart 4 (Fasttracker II worktune)</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/smart4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1998 17:23:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/smart4/</guid><description>A short little jam. Can you spot the trick in track 1 that makes the track swing &amp;lsquo;n shuffle?
P.S. The track plays twice because it is so short.</description></item><item><title>DYCP and music routine on a 386 PC</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/dycp-386/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 1994 18:06:31 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/dycp-386/</guid><description>Coming from the Commodore 64 and being used to coding in assembler, I tried to do the same on my dad&amp;rsquo;s 386 PC. I decided on a DYCP effect, a popular effect in the Commodore 64 demoscene.
The DYCP itself (the bouncy scroller) wasn&amp;rsquo;t too hard; most effort and fun went into the music routine for the Soundblaster&amp;lsquo;s OPL2 (Yamaha YM3812) chip. This is the chip on the Soundblaster that was has a little FM synthesizer in it.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/resume/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/resume/</guid><description>Michel de Bree Freelance Full Stack Java Developer Up-to-date versions available in PDF, Word and online
With 15+ years of experience in complex and dynamic IT landscapes, I am equipped to help you build your automated solutions in an agile and sustainable way.
Currently working with the following techniques:
Scrum / Agile SAFE Java 11 / Spring Boot / Hibernate / PostgreSQL React / REST / JSON / HAL / SOAP / OAuth2 / JWT / OpenAPI (Swagger) Kubernetes / Helm / Docker / Openshift / Linux JUnit / Mockito / Jest / Chai / Enzyme / Wiremock / Cucumber / Selenium Git / Bitbucket / Gitlab / Maven / Jenkins / JIRA / Confluence / SonarQube Personal Information Year of birth: 1972 Residence: The Hague / The Netherlands Languages: Dutch (native), English (fluent) E-mail: michel@micheldebree.</description></item></channel></rss>