<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Michel de Bree</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/</link><description>Recent content on Michel de Bree</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.micheldebree.nl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My favorite font for coding</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/codingfont/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/codingfont/</guid><description>TL;DR: For coding I use Jetbrains Mono, and Iosevka in the terminal.
What make a good font? Link to heading A unique character Link to heading A good font should also have clear distinctions between characters, for example it should be clear that a 0 is not an O, and which is the zero and which the capital O. Another example is 1 and l. This is important because in code, it is not always clear from the context if something is a number or a letter, and computers are very picky.</description></item><item><title>Sunkissed, from the Vandalism #72 soundtrack</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/sunkissed/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/sunkissed/</guid><description>We made an exclusive background tune for the 72nd issue of the Commodore 64 disk magazine Vandalism News. While you are reading the magazine, ours is one of the tunes you can select.
The other tunes in the jukebox are by Laxity, Shogoon, Mutetus, Stinsen, Magnar, Fegolhuzz and Qdor, which is an impressive line-up to be part of!
Some cherry-picked comments:
What a lovely tune!
One .sid in particular really grabbed me, and that was: Sunkissed (8580) Youth &amp;amp; Yavin / Heatwave</description></item><item><title>Terminator 2 theme, from the Endoskull animation</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/endoskull/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/endoskull/</guid><description>I did a little update on the Terminator theme from Big Angry Sprite. It is made for Honcho&amp;rsquo;s entry for the Skull Animation Compo on CSDB: Endoskull. I did not have much time, but I think this version is somewhat of an improvement. And guess what, this little production won 1st place!
P.S. the movie above is taken from the Anniversary Edition, which was released after the competition, and adds a nice opening title screen.</description></item><item><title>Muppetshow Theme, from the demo Subway Art</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/muppetshow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/muppetshow/</guid><description>A cover of the theme from The Muppetshow, made for the successor of the Commodore 64 demo Mahna Mahna, called Subway Art
Again, the music was done by Animal. Nobody knows it&amp;rsquo;s my alter ego, except you, so hush hush&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Retropixels Web GUI</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/retropixels-web/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/retropixels-web/</guid><description>There is now a graphical interface online for Retropixels, the tool I made for converting images to Commodore 64 format. For now it supports multicolor and hires bitmaps, so no sprites or FLI/AFLI. For that you still need the command line tool.
A new feature in this version is the ability to disable certain colors from the palette. This will make it to the command line version aswell, eventually.
The web version is 100% javascript running in your browser, there are no server-side components, so the images you convert never leave your computer.</description></item><item><title>Mahna Mahna, from the demo Mahna Mahna</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/mahnamahna/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/mahnamahna/</guid><description>Pssst&amp;hellip; I made the soundtrack to this Commodore 64 demo, but I did it incognito. Don&amp;rsquo;t tell anyone!</description></item><item><title>The Hangover (after last night with Stinsen)</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/the_hangover/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 08:24:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/the_hangover/</guid><description>It has been about 30 years since Yavin and I collaborated on a Commodore 64 tune, so to celebrate, here is a new tune!
This is our entry to the &amp;ldquo;Last Night&amp;rdquo; melody competition on the Commodore 64 Scene Database, which was organised by Stinsen. The challenge was to come up with a melody for a short little tune that Stinsen made.
This was the starting point:
Last night, by Stinsen</description></item><item><title>Retropixels 0.8.0</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/retropixels-0-8-0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 08:24:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/retropixels-0-8-0/</guid><description>Retropixels is a cross-platform command line tool to convert images to a format that is supported by the legendary Commodore 64 (c-64) home computer. It can output images in the style of the c-64, and also executables that can be run on a real c-64.
Retropixels can be found on Github and in the npm repository
Moving towards a developer tool Link to heading In this release, which is not backwards compatible, retropixels is moving more towards a developer tool for Commodore 64 fanatics.</description></item><item><title>Big Angry Sprite; going back to my Commodore 64 roots</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/big_angry_sprite/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 08:24:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/big_angry_sprite/</guid><description>After 30 years of coding anything for the Commodore 64, I have released a small demo. Back in the 80s I started to teach myself programming on this machine, and I though it would be fun to revisit my coding roots.
The demoscene of the Commodore 64 is still very much alive, and seeing the amazing stuff that is coming out nowadays, I was motivated to try and add a little something to that.</description></item><item><title>Retropixels 0.7.1</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/retropixels-0-7-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 19:07:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/retropixels-0-7-1/</guid><description>Retropixels is a cross-platform command line tool to convert images to a format that is supported by the legendary Commodore 64 (c-64) home computer. It can output images in the style of the c-64, and also executables that can be run on a real c-64.
Retropixels can be found on Github and in the npm repository
New in this version Link to heading In this new version, you can choose between a couple of color palettes, and also a color space to use when the image is quantized, with two new arguments:</description></item><item><title>I built a new personal website with Hugo</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/welcome/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/welcome/</guid><description>Welcome to my website. In this first post I will go over some details on how this site was created.
The site is static HTML, generated by Hugo Sourcecode is accessible on Github The generated HTML is hosted on Github pages Based on the hugo-coder theme So, I didn&amp;rsquo;t use a fancy CMS like Wordpress, or a platform like Medium for example. The main reasons for doing it like this are:</description></item><item><title>Woop woop, an oldskool style HTML5 demo</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/1991/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/1991/</guid><description>In november 2013, a small, quite obscure demoscene gathering called &amp;lsquo;1991&amp;rsquo; took place in Scheveningen/Holland. My friend John wanted to release a HTML5 demo in 1991 style there, and asked me to contribute some parts to that. So here it is:
Start the demo
The bottom three parts in this overview screenshot are made by me. The one on the bottom left is a small tribute to Bas Bron&amp;rsquo;s video clip to You&amp;rsquo;ve got my love.</description></item><item><title>Earwax, 1st place in Beatbattle III</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/beatbattle3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2003 17:36:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/beatbattle3/</guid><description>My tune &amp;ldquo;Earwax&amp;rdquo; came first in the Renoise Beatbattle III!
For this competition the participants were limited to a fixed set of samples you were allowed to use, and a maximum file size of 400kb.</description></item><item><title>Smart 4, a worktune</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/smart4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1998 17:23:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/smart4/</guid><description>A short little jam. Can you spot the trick in track 1 that makes the track swing &amp;rsquo;n shuffle?
P.S. The track plays twice because it is so short.</description></item><item><title>Trouble @ X97</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/trouble/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 1997 17:23:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/trouble/</guid><description>This is our (me and my mate Marvin) entry to the X'97 Takeover music competition.
I started the tune at home and then finished it together with Marvin under less than ideal circumstances at the party place itself. It&amp;rsquo;s certainly a little rough around the edges and basicly unfinished, but hey, there was a deadline and we made it!
We ended up getting a big applause and a low ranking in the results.</description></item><item><title>Surprise, from the X97 surprise competition</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/surprise/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 1997 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/surprise/</guid><description>This is our (me and my mate Afzel) entry to the X'97 Takeover surprise music competition.
The surprise element of the music competition is that we didn&amp;rsquo;t know what the competition was until shortly before the deadline. We were supplied with the samples to use in the tune, and some other limitations, which you can read in the information below.
According to that information we hurried through making this in less than half an hour, using Fasttracker II.</description></item><item><title>That time we went to The Party 6</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/theparty6/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 1996 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/theparty6/</guid><description>Late 1996, we got it into our minds to go visit a demoscene party in Denmark, The Party 6. Although we had left our Commodore 64 days behind at that time, we were still sort of forming a group called &amp;ldquo;Heatwave&amp;rdquo;, making music on Amiga and PC.
We thought it would be cool to go to a big, popular party where demosceners of multiple platforms were present. So off we went (me, Hires, Yavin, Yanic and Yinxs), traveling in Hires&amp;rsquo; car from Leiden in the Netherlands, to Aars in Denmark, some 900+ kilometers.</description></item><item><title>Iceball, a tune made in assembler code</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/iceball/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1996 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/iceball/</guid><description>A tune made in assembler code Link to heading This tune was made on the Commodore 64 home computer somewhere in 1996. Although there were plenty of music editors to create music in by that time, I chose a very arcane way of doing things; by using assembler code.
The reason to do it like this is because I was after the specific sound of the excellent music routine by Laxity, and also to learn about how such a music routine works internally.</description></item><item><title>Bosswing (commodore 64 tune)</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/bosswing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 1995 10:44:05 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/bosswing/</guid><description>A short tune I made on the Commodore 64 using DMC 5.1+. As far as I know it has never been used in any Commodore 64 productions. It has been used in this little fireworks display.
You can also find it on DeepSID. The styling of the video was done using Retropixels
Download D64 floppy image with DMC 5.1+ and the sourcefile of the tune</description></item><item><title>DYCP and music routine on a 386 PC</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/dycp-386/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 1994 18:06:31 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/dycp-386/</guid><description>Coming from the Commodore 64 and being used to coding in assembler, I tried to do the same on my dad&amp;rsquo;s 386 PC. I decided on a DYCP effect, a popular effect in the Commodore 64 demoscene.
The DYCP itself (the bouncy scroller) wasn&amp;rsquo;t too hard; most effort and fun went into the music routine for the Soundblaster&amp;rsquo;s OPL2 (Yamaha YM3812) chip. This is the chip on the Soundblaster that was has a little FM synthesizer in it.</description></item><item><title>Fontastic (MS-DOS utility)</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/fontastic_msdos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 1992 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/fontastic_msdos/</guid><description>I had sort of forgotten about this until I found it on an old CD-ROM. A utility to create an alternative font for the EGA or VGA textmode.
At the time I was using Pascal for the code, because I had some experience with it and I liked the ease with which it could mix Pascal and assembler code.
Check it out on Github</description></item><item><title>Eddies Adventure (commodore 64 demo)</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/eddies_adventure/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 1991 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/eddies_adventure/</guid><description>1991 marked the end of the Commodore 64 era of out little democoding group &amp;ldquo;Heatwave&amp;rdquo;. We didn&amp;rsquo;t know it at the time but we must have felt we wanted to go out with a bang, and make a megademo in which we made everything ourselves.
It was quite common practice to &amp;lsquo;borrow&amp;rsquo; resources like music and fonts from other demos or games. We didn&amp;rsquo;t want to do any of that this time.</description></item><item><title>Fontastic (commodore 64 utility)</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/fontastic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 1990 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/fontastic/</guid><description>After the thrill of making money from coding with Solitair, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d try again and made a utility for drawing your own fonts on the Commodore 64, called Fontastic.
I sent it off to &amp;ldquo;Magic Disk 64&amp;rdquo; again, and got a letter back saying they liked it and were willing to pay for it:
And sure enough, a few months later I saw the magazine with my tool on it in the shop:</description></item><item><title>Solitair (commodore 64 game)</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/solitair/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 1990 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/solitair/</guid><description>The first time I was ever payed for practising one of my biggest hobbies was in 1990, when I was 17 years old. I heard about this disk magazine called &amp;ldquo;Magic Disk 64&amp;rdquo;. This was a magazine you bought in a magazine shop, but instead of it having physical pages, it only had a cover, a piece of cardboard and a floppy disk inside. On the floppy disks was software that was written by amateurs and sold to the magazine.</description></item><item><title>Our point of view</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/our_point_of_view/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 1988 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/our_point_of_view/</guid><description>One of my first ventures in demo coding (see Demoscene) was a very simple picture collection with background music. The pictures were made by my cousin &amp;ldquo;Hires&amp;rdquo;, and by myself, &amp;ldquo;Mad B&amp;rdquo;. I had just figured out how to display a multicolor picture, and how to play a soundmonitor tune.
Our point of view Link to heading Run it in an online emulator or Download it from CSDB
Our point of view 2 Link to heading Run it in an online emulator or Download it from CSDB</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/resume/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/resume/</guid><description>Michel de Bree Link to heading Freelance Full Stack Java Developer Link to heading With over 17 years of experience in complex and dynamic IT landscapes, I am equipped to help you build and run your software in an agile and sustainable way, by taking ownership of every aspect that keeps the software doing what you expect it to do, out there in the real world.
Currently working with the following techniques:</description></item></channel></rss>