<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>music on Michel de Bree</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/tags/music/</link><description>Recent content in music on Michel de Bree</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2003 17:36:53 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.micheldebree.nl/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1st place in Beatbattle III</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/beatbattle3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2003 17:36:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/beatbattle3/</guid><description>My tune &amp;ldquo;Earwax&amp;rdquo; came first in the Renoise Beatbattle III!
For this competition the participants were limited to a fixed set of samples you were allowed to use, and a maximum file size of 400kb.</description></item><item><title>Smart 4 (Fasttracker II worktune)</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/smart4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1998 17:23:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/smart4/</guid><description>A short little jam. Can you spot the trick in track 1 that makes the track swing &amp;lsquo;n shuffle?
P.S. The track plays twice because it is so short.</description></item><item><title>Trouble (Fasttracker II tune)</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/trouble/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 1997 17:23:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/trouble/</guid><description>This is our (me and my mate Marvin) entry to the X'97 Takeover music competition.
I started the tune at home and then finished it together with Marvin under less than ideal circumstances at the party place itself. It&amp;rsquo;s certainly a little rough around the edges and basicly unfinished, but hey, there was a deadline and we made it!
We ended up getting a big applause and a low ranking in the results.</description></item><item><title>Iceball (commodore 64 tune)</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/iceball/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1996 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/iceball/</guid><description>A tune made in assembler code This tune was made on the Commodore 64 home computer somewhere in 1996. Although there were plenty of music editors to create music in by that time, I chose a very arcane way of doing things; by using assembler code.
The reason to do it like this is because I was after the specific sound of the excellent music routine by Laxity, and also to learn about how such a music routine works internally.</description></item><item><title>Bosswing (commodore 64 tune)</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/bosswing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 1995 10:44:05 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/bosswing/</guid><description>A short tune I made on the Commodore 64 using DMC 5.1+. As far as I know it has never been used in any Commodore 64 productions.
You can also find it on DeepSID. The styling of the video was done using Retropixels
Download D64 floppy image with DMC 5.1+ and the sourcefile of the tune</description></item><item><title>DYCP and music routine on a 386 PC</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/dycp-386/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 1994 18:06:31 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/dycp-386/</guid><description>Coming from the Commodore 64 and being used to coding in assembler, I tried to do the same on my dad&amp;rsquo;s 386 PC. I decided on a DYCP effect, a popular effect in the Commodore 64 demoscene.
The DYCP itself (the bouncy scroller) wasn&amp;rsquo;t too hard; most effort and fun went into the music routine for the Soundblaster&amp;rsquo;s OPL2 (Yamaha YM3812) chip. This is the chip on the Soundblaster that was has a little FM synthesizer in it.</description></item></channel></rss>