<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>c64 on Michel de Bree</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/tags/c64/</link><description>Recent content in c64 on Michel de Bree</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 08:24:49 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.micheldebree.nl/tags/c64/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Retropixels 0.8.0 released</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/retropixels-0-8-0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 08:24:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/retropixels-0-8-0/</guid><description>Retropixels is a cross-platform command line tool to convert images to a format that is supported by the legendary Commodore 64 (c-64) home computer. It can output images in the style of the c-64, and also executables that can be run on a real c-64.
Retropixels can be found on Github and in the npm repository
Moving towards a developer tool In this release, which is not backwards compatible, retropixels is moving more towards a developer tool for Commodore 64 fanatics.</description></item><item><title>Big Angry Sprite; going back to my Commodore 64 roots</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/big_angry_sprite/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 08:24:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/big_angry_sprite/</guid><description>After 30 years of coding anything for the Commodore 64, I have released a small demo. Back in the 80s I started to teach myself programming on this machine, and I though it would be fun to revisit my coding roots.
The demoscene of the Commodore 64 is still very much alive, and seeing the amazing stuff that is coming out nowadays, I was motivated to try and add a little something to that.</description></item><item><title>Retropixels 0.7.1 released</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/retropixels-0-7-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 19:07:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/retropixels-0-7-1/</guid><description>Retropixels is a cross-platform command line tool to convert images to a format that is supported by the legendary Commodore 64 (c-64) home computer. It can output images in the style of the c-64, and also executables that can be run on a real c-64.
Retropixels can be found on Github and in the npm repository
New in this version In this new version, you can choose between a couple of color palettes, and also a color space to use when the image is quantized, with two new arguments:</description></item><item><title>Iceball (commodore 64 tune)</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/iceball/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1996 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/iceball/</guid><description>A tune made in assembler code This tune was made on the Commodore 64 home computer somewhere in 1996. Although there were plenty of music editors to create music in by that time, I chose a very arcane way of doing things; by using assembler code.
The reason to do it like this is because I was after the specific sound of the excellent music routine by Laxity, and also to learn about how such a music routine works internally.</description></item><item><title>Bosswing (commodore 64 tune)</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/bosswing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 1995 10:44:05 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/bosswing/</guid><description>A short tune I made on the Commodore 64 using DMC 5.1+. As far as I know it has never been used in any Commodore 64 productions.
You can also find it on DeepSID. The styling of the video was done using Retropixels
Download D64 floppy image with DMC 5.1+ and the sourcefile of the tune</description></item><item><title>DYCP and music routine on a 386 PC</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/dycp-386/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 1994 18:06:31 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/dycp-386/</guid><description>Coming from the Commodore 64 and being used to coding in assembler, I tried to do the same on my dad&amp;rsquo;s 386 PC. I decided on a DYCP effect, a popular effect in the Commodore 64 demoscene.
The DYCP itself (the bouncy scroller) wasn&amp;rsquo;t too hard; most effort and fun went into the music routine for the Soundblaster&amp;rsquo;s OPL2 (Yamaha YM3812) chip. This is the chip on the Soundblaster that was has a little FM synthesizer in it.</description></item></channel></rss>