<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tracker on Michel de Bree</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/tags/tracker/</link><description>Recent content in tracker on Michel de Bree</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2003 17:36:53 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.micheldebree.nl/tags/tracker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Earwax, 1st place in Beatbattle III</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/beatbattle3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2003 17:36:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/beatbattle3/</guid><description>My tune &amp;ldquo;Earwax&amp;rdquo; came first in the Renoise Beatbattle III!
For this competition the participants were limited to a fixed set of samples you were allowed to use, and a maximum file size of 400kb.</description></item><item><title>Smart 4, a worktune</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/smart4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1998 17:23:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/smart4/</guid><description>A short little jam. Can you spot the trick in track 1 that makes the track swing &amp;rsquo;n shuffle?
P.S. The track plays twice because it is so short.</description></item><item><title>Trouble @ X97</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/trouble/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 1997 17:23:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/trouble/</guid><description>This is our (me and my mate Marvin) entry to the X'97 Takeover music competition.
I started the tune at home and then finished it together with Marvin under less than ideal circumstances at the party place itself. It&amp;rsquo;s certainly a little rough around the edges and basicly unfinished, but hey, there was a deadline and we made it!
We ended up getting a big applause and a low ranking in the results.</description></item><item><title>Surprise, from the X97 surprise competition</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/surprise/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 1997 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/surprise/</guid><description>This is our (me and my mate Afzel) entry to the X'97 Takeover surprise music competition.
The surprise element of the music competition is that we didn&amp;rsquo;t know what the competition was until shortly before the deadline. We were supplied with the samples to use in the tune, and some other limitations, which you can read in the information below.
According to that information we hurried through making this in less than half an hour, using Fasttracker II.</description></item><item><title>That time we went to The Party 6</title><link>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/theparty6/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 1996 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.micheldebree.nl/posts/theparty6/</guid><description>Late 1996, we got it into our minds to go visit a demoscene party in Denmark, The Party 6. Although we had left our Commodore 64 days behind at that tine, we were still sort of forming a group called &amp;ldquo;Heatwave&amp;rdquo;, making music on Amiga and PC.
We thought it would be cool to go to a big, popular party where demosceners of multiple platforms were present. So off we went (me, Hires, Yavin, Yanic and Yinxs), traveling in Hires&amp;rsquo; car from Leiden in the Netherlands, to Aars in Denmark, some 900+ kilometers.</description></item></channel></rss>